二零二三年陕西省初中学业水平考试英语听力部分。二零二三年陕西省初中学业水平考试英语听力部分。第一大题，听选答案。第一节，听下面十段对话，每段对话后有一个问题，读两遍，请根据每段对话的内容。和后面的问题，从所给的三个选项中选出最恰当的一项。
赵强？
Question, what food would the man like?
Good afternoon, sir.
May I take your order?
Yes, I'd like some dumplings, please.
Question, what food would the man like?
food what food like?
like? food would like?
Excuse me, is there a bookstore near here?
Yes, there is one next to Bank of China on Chang 'an Road.
You can take bus number 603 there.
Question, where's the bookstore?
Number six, Peter,
please keep your voice down.
We should be quiet in the library.
Sorry, Miss Zhang.
Question, what does the woman ask the boy to do?
Peter, please keep your voice down.
We should be quiet in the library.
Sorry, Miss Zhang.
Question, what does the woman ask the boy to do?
Number seven, it's Sunday today.
You got up so early.
Oh, yeah, because I'm going to climb the mountain with my classmates.
Question, why did the boy get up early?
It's Sunday today.
You got up so early.
Oh, yeah, because I'm going to climb the mountain with my classmates.
Question, why did the boy get up early?
Number eight, you did a good job in the art festival.
Thanks, Mom. I really enjoyed it.
Question, who are the two speakers?
You did a good job in the art festival.
Thanks, Mom. I really enjoyed it.
Question, who are the two speakers?
Number nine, your gift box is so special.
Is it made of wood?
No, it isn't.
It's made of paper.
Question, what's the box made of?
Your gift box is so special.
Is it made of wood?
No, it isn't.
It's made of paper.
Question, what's the box made of?
Number ten, it's nine o now.
When shall we meet at the old people's home?
Ten minutes later.
Remember to take the gifts we made yesterday.
Okay. Question, time will they meet?
It's nine o now.
When shall we meet at the old people's home?
Ten minutes later.
Remember to take the gifts we made yesterday.
Okay. what time will they meet?
第二节，听下面两段对话。每。一段对话后有几道小题，请根据对话的内容，从题目所给的三个选项中选出问题的正确答案。每段对话读两遍。听第十一段对话，回答第十一、十二小题。
Hello, Li Hao.
What are you going to do this Thursday?
Hello, Mrs. I'm going to celebrate the Dragon Bolt Festival.
It's a traditional festival in China.
What do you usually do that day?
We usually watch Dragon Bolt races and
粽子
to remember Qu Yuan.
He was one of the greatest poets in ancient China.
Oh, I see.
What a special festival it is!
Hello, Li Hao.
What are you going to do this Thursday?
Hello, Mrs. I'm going to celebrate the Dragon Bolt Festival.
It's a traditional festival in China.
What do you usually do that day?
We usually watch Dragon Bolt races and eat to remember
粽子屈原.
He was one of the greatest poets in ancient China.
Oh, I see.
What a special festival it is!
听第十二段对话，回答第十三至十五小题。
Mrs. White. Bolt Congratulations, David!
You won first prize in the tennis competition yesterday.
Good job! Thank you, Wang
You know, I'm good at it, and I tried my best.
Do you often play tennis in your free time?
Yes, I play it every Tuesday and Friday in our school club.
What sport do you usually do?
I usually swim with my mother.
It's relaxing. How often do you go swimming?
Three times a week.
Great! Exercise really keeps us healthy and strong.
What sport I David!
You won first prize in the tennis competition yesterday.
Good job! Thank you, Wang
You know, I'm good at it, and I tried my best.
Do you often play tennis in your free time?
Yes, I play it every Tuesday and Friday in our school club.
What sport do you usually do?
I usually swim with my mother.
It's relaxing. How often do you go swimming?
Three times a week.
Great! Exercise really keeps us healthy and strong.
第二大题。听填信息。本题你将听到一段独白，读两遍，
Ting. Hello, everyone!
请根据独白内容，用所听到的单词或短语完成下列个体，每空不超过三个单词。
Today, I'd like to talk about a kind of birds that are famous in Shanxi province.
It's Zhu Huan bird.
It is one of the four treasures of the Qinlin Mountains.
A Zhu Huan bird has a red beak and white feathers.
A beak, B -E -A -K, is the heart -pointed mouth of a bird.
And feathers, F -E -A -T -H -E -R -S, are the light soft things that cover a bird's
body. This kind of birds is valuable.
In the 20th century, people could hardly see any of them at any place in the world.
In the year 1981, only seven Zhu Huan birds were found in the Qinlin Mountains.
People have done many things in order to increase the number of Zhu Huan birds.
There are over 7,000 birds in our country today.
What a great success we Chinese have made in animal protection.
As students, we should take action to protect wild animals that are in danger.
Hello everyone. Today, I'd like to talk about a kind of birds that are famous in
Shanxi province. It's Zhu Huan bird.
It is one of the four treasures of the Qinlin Mountains.
A Zhu Huan bird has a red beak and white feathers.
A B -E -A -K, is the heart -pointed mouth of a bird.
And feathers, F -E -A -T -H -E -R -S, are the light soft things that cover a bird's
body. This kind of birds is valuable.
In the 20th century,
people could hardly see any of them at any place in the world.
In the year 1981, only seven Zhu Huan birds were found in the Qinlin Mountains.
People have done many things in order to increase the number of Zhu birds.
There are over 7,000 birds in our country today.
What a great success we Chinese have made in animal protection.
As students, we should take action to protect wild animals that are in danger.
This is the end
听力部分到此结束。现在，请同学们将所选答案转涂在答题卡的相应位置。然后继续作答笔试部分试题。